<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-17T22:08:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Drawdown Windsor</title><subtitle>Drawdown is a 2017 book edited by Paul Hawken that 'maps, measures, models, and describes the 100 most substantive solutions to global warming.' Drawdown Windsor is a blog by Mita Williams that applies that model to the Windsor, Ontario, Canada.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Asking the climate question</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/asking-the-climate-question.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Asking the climate question" /><published>2017-05-22T19:13:07-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-22T19:13:07-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/asking-the-climate-question</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/asking-the-climate-question.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… the City also needs to develop on-going strategies that will continue to address the changing climate over the long-term. The 
following strategies should be undertaken to ensure that the City of Windsor continues to be a leader on adaptation well into the future:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Incorporate climate change adaptation into city policies and high level plans;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create internal mechanisms to ‘ask the climate question’ for all new major infrastructure 
projects&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Monitor climate change, evaluate the effectiveness of adaptation strategies and adjust as 
needed (adaptive management);&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Use best available science to analyze how the climate is changing locally and how this may 
impact the community;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Routinely review the City of Windsor’s vulnerability to climate change;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Continuously conduct risk assessments to identify priority impacts requiring adaptation actions,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Engage the public, business and other stakeholder groups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.citywindsor.ca/residents/environment/environmental-master-plan/documents/windsor%20climate%20change%20adaptation%20plan.pdf&quot;&gt;2012 City of Windsor Climate Change Adaption Plan (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can city councillors ask whether ‘the climate question’ was addressed when new major infrastructure is reported on in council?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">… the City also needs to develop on-going strategies that will continue to address the changing climate over the long-term. The following strategies should be undertaken to ensure that the City of Windsor continues to be a leader on adaptation well into the future: Incorporate climate change adaptation into city policies and high level plans; Create internal mechanisms to ‘ask the climate question’ for all new major infrastructure projects; Monitor climate change, evaluate the effectiveness of adaptation strategies and adjust as needed (adaptive management); Use best available science to analyze how the climate is changing locally and how this may impact the community; Routinely review the City of Windsor’s vulnerability to climate change; Continuously conduct risk assessments to identify priority impacts requiring adaptation actions, Engage the public, business and other stakeholder groups.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Drawdown Windsor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/welcome-to-drawdownwindsor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Drawdown Windsor" /><published>2017-05-22T18:48:07-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-22T18:48:07-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/welcome-to-drawdownwindsor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/welcome-to-drawdownwindsor.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drawdown.org/&quot;&gt;Drawdown&lt;/a&gt; is a 2017 book edited by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Hawken&quot;&gt;Paul Hawken&lt;/a&gt; that ‘maps, measures, models, and describes the 100 most substantive solutions to global warming.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawdown Windsor is a blog by &lt;a href=&quot;http://aedileworks.com/&quot;&gt;Mita Williams&lt;/a&gt; that applies the recommendations of the book to Windsor, Ontario, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://upcoming.org/@copystar?when=past&quot;&gt;Repair The World&lt;/a&gt; which is a monthly meetup hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackf.org/&quot;&gt;Hackforge&lt;/a&gt; for related events and community activities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Drawdown is a 2017 book edited by Paul Hawken that ‘maps, measures, models, and describes the 100 most substantive solutions to global warming.’</summary></entry></feed>